Guide to the Peter Viereck papers,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
Peter Viereck papers,
1815-2006
Viereck, Peter, 1916-2006
83.7 linear feet ( 89 document boxes, 30 record storage cartons, 1 flat box)
Columbia University. Rare Book and Manuscript Library, New York, NY. 10027
MS#1412
6134809
The papers of the historian, poet, and conservative political theorist Peter Viereck (1916-2006), his father, George Sylvester Viereck (1884–1962), and other family members.
Biographical Note
Peter Viereck (1916-2006) was a seminal figure in American conservative thought as well as an award-winning poet and historian who won Guggenheim Fellowships in both poetry and history. Viereck wrote prolifically on politics and intellectual history, and published over a dozen collections of poetry, most recently Door: Poems (2005). In 1949 Viereck won the Pulitzer Prize for his first book of poems, Terror and Decorum. Often credited with launching and naming the modern conservative intellectual movement in the late 1940s, Viereck later criticized its direction and deplored Senator Joseph McCarthy for betraying authentic conservative values. He was professor of Russian and European history at Mount Holyoke College for nearly fifty years
Peter Viereck's father, George Sylvester Viereck (1884-1962), played a prominent role in the literary and cultural scene of early twentieth-century America, inspiring and serving as the first secretary of the Poetry Society of America. As a free-lance writer for publications including The Saturday Evening Post, George Sylvester Viereck interviewed many leading figures, including Albert Einstein and Adolph Hitler, and was a friend of Sigmund Freud. During World War II, the elder Viereck's standing was destroyed by his support for Nazi Germany as a paid propagandist. He was arrested and jailed for five years as an unregistered agent of Germany, although espionage charges against him were ultimately dropped. During his imprisonment, his younger son died in U.S. military service at Anzio, Italy, deepening George Sylvester Viereck's rift with his elder son Peter, who served as a U.S. Army intelligence analyst during the war. Peter Viereck had already diagnosed the evils of Nazi Germany in his book Metapolitics: From the Romantics to Hitler, begun at Harvard in 1936 and first published three months before the attack on Pearl Harbor.
Scope and Content
The collection includes letters, manuscripts, documents, photographs, tapes, printed material, and memorabilia of Peter Viereck (1916-2006) and those of his father, George Sylvester Viereck (1884-1962), and mother, Margaret Hein Viereck. Some of the notable correspondents are Daniel Boorstin, Joseph Brodsky, Sigmund Freud, W.V.O. Quine, Arthur Schlesinger Jr., George Bernard Shaw, Kaiser Wilhelm II, and William Carlos Williams. There are extensive files of manuscripts of Viereck's work, as well as those of his father. In addition, there are numerous files which contain photographs of the Viereck family and their friends and associates.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged in ten series.
Series I: Correspondence, 1926-2005
Subseries I.1: Individual Correspondents, 1926-2005
Subseries I.2: Institutions and Subjects, 1936-2005
Series II: Research Notes and Clippings, 1815-2002
Series III: Drafts and Outlines, 1930s-2001
Series IV: Reviews and Criticism of Viereck's Work, 1940s-2003
Series V: Photographs, 1937-2000
Series VI: George S. Viereck, 1903-1989
Series VII: Margaret Hein Viereck and Other Family Members, 1911-1979
Series VIII: Subject Files, 1935-2004
Series IX: Personal Documents and Artifacts, 1933-1993
Series X: Audiovisual Material, 1985-1997
Subjects
Auden, W.H. (Wystan Hugh), 1907-1973.; Barber, Evelyn M.; Bell, Daniel, 1919-; United States--Intellectual life--20th century.; United States--Politics and government--1945-1989.; Russia History--20th century.; Bettelheim, Bruno.; Brodsky, Joseph, 1940-1996.; D'Evelyn, Thomas.; Heckscher, August, 1913-1997.; Ryn, Claes, G., 1943-; Schlesinger, Arthur M. (Arthur Meier), 1917-2007.; Sontag, Susan, 1933-2004.; Conservatism.; National socialism.; Germany--Civilization.; Russian poetry--20th century--History and criticism.; Authors, American--20th century--Biography.; German Americans--Biography.; World War, 1939-1945--German Americans.; Correspondence.; Poetry.
Access Restrictions
This collection has no restrictions.
This collection is located off-site. You will need to request this material at least twenty-four (24) hours in advance to use the collection in the Rare Book and Manuscript Library reading room.
Purchase from Lame Duck Books, July 2006.
- Series I: Correspondence, 1926-2005
  The correspondence is extensive and wide-ranging. There are many prominent writers, politicians, philosophers and poets and historians noted, such as: George Santayana; Henry Cabot Lodge; C. S. Lewis; Wendell Willkie; W. H. Auden; Robert Graves; Wallace Stevens; Carl Sandburg; Stephen Spender; Susan Sontag; and George Santayana. There are also significant files of family correspondence.
  - Subseries I.1: Individual Correspondents, 1926-2005
    Subseries 1 is arranged alphabetically by the last name of the individual.
    - Albert, H. F., 1954 (Box 106)
    - Arendt, Hannah, 1951 (Box 97)
    - Attik, Anne, 1992 (Box 63)
    - Auden, W.H., 1946-1950 (Box 52)
    - Barber, Evelyn M., 1979-1996 (Box 111)
    - Barzun, Jacques, 1952 (Box 96)
    - Bateson, F.W. 1955-1956 (Box 1)
    - Bauschinger, Sigrid, 1993-1998 (Box 7)
    - Beer, Sam, 1983-1991 (Box 117)
    - Beeson, Jack, 2002-2003 (Box 9, 20)
    - Behnfeldt, Carla, 1980s, undated (Box 113)
    - Bell, Canon Bernard Iddings, 1950s (Box 96)
    - Bell, Daniel, 1961-1987 (Box 9, 20, 111)
    - Benedikt, Michael, 1975-1979 (Box 2)
    - Benfey, Christopher, 1980s (Box 103)
    - Bennett, Evelyn--with Conservatism drafts, 1970s (Box 104)
    - Benton, Thomas, 1951 (Box 118)
    - Berenson, Bernard, 1946-1953 (Box 52)
    - Berenson, Ruth, 1986 (Box 38)
    - Berger, Jean, 1972-1977 (Box 113)
    - Bering, Mrs., 1991 (Box 111)
    - Berman, Phillip, 1987 (Box 103)
    - Bernstein, Leonard, 1971 (Box 52)
    - Berlin, Isaiah, 1958 (Box 52)
    - Bettleheim, Bruno, 1971-1978 (Box 52, 96)
    - Bialosky, Jill--Norton & Company, 1989 (Box 5)
    - Billington, James, 1980 (Box 103)
    - Binion, Rudolph, 1983-1999 (Box 113)
    - Blake, Patricia, 1962 (Box 44)
    - Bloom, Harold, 1977 (Box 63)
    - Blum, John, 1970s (Box 103)
    - Boorstein, Daniel, 1951-1970 (Box 96)
    - Borody, Wayne, 2005 (Box 20)
    - Bowles, Charles, 1950s (Box 96)
    - Brann, Jim, 1990 (Box 106)
    - Brace, Harcourt, 1987 (Box 113)
    - Breit, Peter K., 2001 (Box 113)
    - Brekke, Linzy, 1996-1997 (Box 102)
    - Breit, P.K., undated (Box 111)
    - Brodsky, Joseph, 1969-1970 (Box 90-92, 94)
    - Brody, Polly, undated (Box 102)
    - Brody, Stephanie, 1978 (Box 105)
    - Brooks, Gwendolyn, 1959 (Box 52)
    - Bruning, Heinrich, 1937-1938 (Box 113)
    - Brush, Douglas, 1967-1977 (Box 96)
    - Buckley, W.M. Jr., 1950s (Box 56)
    - Burgin, Richard, 1993-2004 (Box 34, 111)
    - Byxbe, Rita, 1980-2001 (Box 19, 43, 90)
    - Campbell, Roy, 1957-1980s (Box 52, 104)
    - Carruth, Haydn, 1951 (Box 97)
    - Case, Clifford P, 1950-1972 (Box 97)
    - Castilla, Alberto, 1980s (Box 103)
    - Chametzky, J., 1980s (Box 103)
    - Clark, Betsy, 1960s-1970s (Box 103)
    - Cowley, Malcolm, 1981 (Box 104)
    - Cox, Nigel, 1997 (Box 103)
    - Cook, Thomas, 1963-1965 (Box 18)
    - Crawford, Alan, 1973-1993 (Box 65)
    - Craig, Gordon, 2004 (Box 34)
    - Crod, Elena?, 1964, undated (Box 104)
    - Crowley, Robert, 1951-1956, 1975 (Box 118)
    - Currier, Warren, 1980s (Box 103)
    - Dali, Salvador, 1950 (Box 52)
    - Daiches, David, 1950-1952 (Box 97)
    - Dario, Gina, circa 1996 (Box 102)
    - Davidson, Nicholas, 1976-1992 (Box 97)
    - Davis, Robert G., 1950s-1990s (Box 38)
    - Davis, Elmer, 1949-1953 (Box 97)
    - Deak, Istvan, 2004 (Box 19)
    - de Fremery, Robert, 1990s (Box 103)
    - de Grazia, Victoria, 1970s-1980s (Box 103)
    - Delacorte, George, 1960s (Box 103)
    - D'Evelyn, Thomas, 1953-2000 (Box 15, 77, 103, 111)
    - Dorman, Sarah Wheeler, 1996 (Box 102)
    - Dorn, Alfred, 1988 (Box 111)
    - Douglas, Lord Alfred, 1938 (Box 52)
    - Dove, Rita, 1993-1995 (Box 111)
    - Eastman, Max, 1954-1986 (Box 104)
    - Ehrenburg, Ilya Grigoryevich, 1963 September 16 (Box 46, 90)
    - Ehrle, Richard, 1990s (Box 103)
    - Ehlers, Anke, 1988-1989 (Box 103)
    - Einstein, Elsa to Margaret Viereck, 1932 February 22 (Box 34)
    - Eklof-Carlson, Jocelyn, 1986-1987 (Box 108)
    - Eldridge, Paul, 1977-1981 (Box 105)
    - Ellis, Virginia, undated (Box 103)
    - English, Helen--Maurice English Poetry Award, 1980s (Box 37)
    - English, Maurice, 1970s (Box 13, 37)
    - Erikson, Kai of Yale Review, 1986 (Box 4)
    - Exner, Richard, 1980-1981 (Box 111)
    - Fahim, Mayraj,1983-1984 (Box 102)
    - Fairlie, Henry (New Republic), 1982-1983 (Box 15)
    - Field, Andrew, 1980s-1990s (Box 103)
    - Filler, Louis, 1960s-1980s (Box 96)
    - Fischer, Berta, 1936 (Box 105)
    - Freud, Sigmund, 1935 (Box 52)
    - Frost, Robert, undated (Box 52)
    - Fulda, Ludwig to Margaret Viereck, 1936 February 20 (Box 34)
    - Garland, Joseph, 1995 (Box 106)
    - Garlick, Dr. Alan, 1996-1997 (Box 111)
    - George Braziller, Inc., 1979, 2001 (Box 7)
    - Emery, George, 1988-1991 (Box 113)
    - Gertz, Elmer, 1952-1991 (Box 96)
    - Gioia, Dana, 1980s (Box 103)
    - Glaze, Andrew, 1972-1986 (Box 113)
    - Goldman, Eric, 1964-1974 (Box 97)
    - Goldstein, Kimberley, undated (Box 19)
    - Golffing, Francis, 1980-1994, undated (Box 113)
    - Grant, Frederic, 1946, undated (Box 105)
    - Graves, Robert, 1950s (Box 52, 97)
    - Grunes, Dorothy, 1999 (Box 102)
    - Guerard, Albert, 1941-1954 (Box 97)
    - Hamburger, Michael, 1966-2002 (Box 7)
    - Hall, Daniel, 1989 (Box 111)
    - Hall, J.G., 1954-1979 (Box 64)
    - Halper, Ross, 1994-1995 (Box 106)
    - Harder, Rosemary, 1999 (Box 111)
    - Harper, Joyce, 1999 (Box 102)
    - Harris, Luida, 1994, undated (Box 111)
    - Hart, Jeffrey, 1988 (Box 111)
    - Heaney, Seamus, 1980s (Box 52)
    - Heckscher, August, 1929-1972 (Box 97)
    - Hedley, Leslie Woolf, 1989-1990 (Box 111)
    - Henault, Marie, 1964-1972 (Box 111)
    - Hoffman, Daniel, 1990s (Box 111)
    - Hoffmann, Peter, 1978 (Box 45)
    - Hoke, Kathy Rogers, 1995 (Box 103)
    - Hollander, John, 1975 (Box 111)
    - Hook, Sidney, undated (Box 97)
    - Hope, Warren, 1979-1986 (Box 111)
    - Horowitz, Irving and others--Transaction Publishers, 2004 (Box 32-34)
    - Horton, Odette Eldridge, 1998-1999 (Box 106)
    - Howe, Irving, 1950s-1960s (Box 111)
    - Hughes, Cassandra, 1972 (Box 45)
    - Jacobson, Josephine, 1968-1994 (Box 3)
    - Johnson, Kirstin, 1994 (Box 102)
    - Johnson, Neil, 1966-1973 (Box 105)
    - Kalischer, Clemens, 1987 (Box 111)
    - Kazin, Alfred, 1986-1987 (Box 111)
    - Kearney, Deborah, 2000-2002 (Box 34)
    - Keller, Phyllis, 1967-1978 (Box 105)
    - Kline, George, 1980s- December 22, 1998 (Box 45, 107)
    - Kissinger, Nancy, 1964-1975 (Box 111)
    - Koestler, Arthur, 1961 (Box 52)
    - Kohn, Hans, 1938-1954 (Box 52)
    - Kopelev, Orlova, 1960s (Box 45)
    - Kostelanetz, Richard, 1987 (Box 111)
    - Krauthammer, Charles (New Republic), 1983-1985 (Box 15)
    - Kuasowska, Malgonate, 1990s (Box 102)
    - Kuehnelt-Leddihn, Christiane, 1950-1984 (Box 65)
    - Kumin, Maxine, 1970s-1980s (Box 1)
    - Kunitz, Stanley, 1980s (Box 111)
    - Lamont, Corliss, 1950s (Box 96)
    - Leander, Folke, 1975 (Box 65)
    - Lehman, Imogene, 1990s (Box 111)
    - Lehmann, Wilhelm, 1960s (Box 47)
    - Leibowitz, Herbert, July 16, 1981 (Box 4)
    - Lescault, John (actor) concerning performance of Round, 1980 (Box 8)
    - Levin, Harry, 1950s-1980s, undated (Box 9, 105)
    - Lieberman, Larry, 1974-1998 (Box 111)
    - Lifshitz-Losev, Lev, 1978-1979 (Box 106)
    - Lind, Michael, 1995-1998 (Box 5, 6)
    - Lippmann, Walter, 1954-1980s (Box 104)
    - Lish, Gordan, 1986-1987 (Box 111)
    - Lombardi, Karen, 2005 (Box 20)
    - Lowe, Jennifer, 1995-2000 (Box 111)
    - Lowell, Robert (Box 52)
    - Lovejoy, Arthur, 1941-1945 (Box 118)
    - Lukacs, Georg, 1963 September 9 (Box 46)
    - Lukacs, John, 1960s-1980s (Box 105)
    - Lyons, Paul, 2005 (Box 20)
    - Macdonald, Dwight--with Notes and Articles, 1950s (Box 105)
    - MacLeigh, Archibald, 1951, undated (Box 105)
    - Malina, Judith, 1989 (Box 111)
    - Mann, Thomas, 1940s (Box 47, 52)
    - Mann, Klaus, 1940s (Box 52)
    - Markham, Edwin, 1931 (Box 52)
    - Markov family, 1961 (Box 105)
    - Marlow, Louise, undated (Box 111)
    - Martini, F., 1960s (Box 47)
    - McCauley, Gerard, undated (Box 111)
    - McDowell, Robert, 1987-1998 (Box 7)
    - McFadden, Cyra, 1981 (Box 111)
    - McPherson, Sandra, undated (Box 1)
    - Means, Elizabeth Rose Thayer, 1991-1994 (Box 108)
    - Merrill, James (Box 52)
    - Meyer, Helmut, 1980s (Box 47)
    - Moore, Marianne, 1950 (Box 52)
    - Morales, Mary Eugenia, undated (Box 102)
    - Mount Holyoke alumni, circa 1993 (Box 6)
    - Mueller, Lisel, 1980s (Box 1)
    - Mumford, Lewis, 1950 (Box 52)
    - Myers, Marty, 1990-1996 (Box 111)
    - Neff, Emery, 1951 (Box 105)
    - Niebuhr, Reingold, 1950s-1980s (Box 111)
    - Nims, John, circa 1980s (Box 105)
    - Noguere, 1980-1981 (Box 3)
    - O'Donnell, James Preston, 1970s-1980s (Box 38)
    - O'Hehir, Diana, 1987-1989 (Box 3)
    - Oleson, Gary, 1995 (Box 105)
    - Ostriker, Alicia (Box 3)
    - Palmer, John, 1943-1949 (Box 52)
    - Panofsky, Erwin, 1950 (Box 52)
    - Peacock, Molly, 1985-1988 (Box 76)
    - Peck, John, 1998 (Box 45)
    - Peretz, Martin (New Republic), 1987-1996 (Box 15)
    - Pettingell, Phoebe, 1978-1989 (Box 104, 111)
    - Peyre, 1950s (Box 105)
    - Phelan, Anne, 1961 (Box 38)
    - Phillips, Ruth, 1987 (Box 20)
    - Pinksy, Robert, 2000 (Box 97)
    - Pipes, Richard, 1975-1981 (Box 106)
    - Podhoretz, 1980s (Box 111)
    - Pound, Ezra, undated (Box 52)
    - Praz, Mario, undated (Box 52)
    - Pyle, Cynthia, 2000 (Box 111)
    - Quine, Willard Van Orman, 1952-1974 (Box 52)
    - Ransom, John, 1951-1955, 1967 (Box 52, 118)
    - Raditsa, undated (Box 105)
    - Regarding translations of George Viereck, 1961-1970 (Box 113)
    - Reisinger, Curt, 1957-1964 (Box 105)
    - Remnick, David, 1974-2002 (Box 104)
    - Rexroth, Kenneth, 1950 (Box 118)
    - Rheannon, Francesca, 2001 (Box 47)
    - Ricks, Christopher, 1988-1989 (Box 111)
    - Rich, Adrienne, 1950s (Box 118)
    - Riesman, David, 1951-1954, 1957 (Box 118)
    - Riess, Tom, 2002 (Box 33)
    - Rodman, Selden, 1950s (Box 105)
    - Roe, Priscilla, 1999 (Box 111)
    - Roethke, Theodore, undated (Box 2, 118)
    - Roskolenko, Harry, 1972 (Box 105)
    - Rostow, Elspeth--With Article, 1988 (Box 111)
    - Rothschild, Ernest, 1970s (Box 104)
    - Rubin, Louis D., 1977-1987 (Box 111)
    - Russell, Kirk, 1952-1954 (Box 5)
    - Ryn, Claes, 1979-1997 (Box 37-38, 110)
    - Safire, William, 1979-1980 (Box 5)
    - Saiger, George M., 1991 (Box 105)
    - Salter, Mary Jo, 1990-1994 (Box 111)
    - Salvemini, 1950s (Box 105)
    - Sandburg,Carl, 1954 (Box 118)
    - Santayana, George, 1940s (Box 78, 118)
    - Scemla, Miriam, 1944 (Box 105)
    - Schenkel, Elmar, 1989 (Box 44)
    - Schlesinger, Arthur, 2002 (Box 18)
    - Schlessinger, Arthur, Jr., 1941-2005, undated (Box 34, 95, 118)
    - Schnackenberg, Gertrude, 1982-1987 (Box 77)
    - Schorer, Mark, 1948 (Box 105)
    - Schwartz, Delmore, 1950 (Box 118)
    - Schwartz, Paul--With Writings, 1984, undated (Box 111)
    - Sereny, Gitta, 1910s (Box 111)
    - Shapiro, Karl, 1987-1993 (Box 37, 118)
    - Shapiro, Karl, 1948-1985 (Box 9, 118)
    - Shaw, George Bernard, 1938-1940s (Box 81, 84, 105, 118)
    - Shaw-Kaiser for George and Peter Viereck, 1926, 1938-1939 (Box 118)
    - Shulman, Alix Kates, 1980s (Box 111)
    - Silvers, Robert, 1974-1988 (Box 104)
    - Simpson, Louis, 1951 (Box 97)
    - Sinclair, Upton, 1950s (Box 105, 118)
    - Sitwell, Edith, 1949 (Box 118)
    - Snow, Karen, 1970s (Box 103)
    - Sontag, Susan, 1985-2000 (Box 97, 111)
    - Spencer, Theodore, 1940s (Box 105)
    - Spender, Stephen, 1960s (Box 118)
    - Stade, George, 1970s (Box 111)
    - Steiner, George, 1987 (Box 111)
    - Stewart, Walter E., 1988-1989 (Box 111)
    - Stevens,Wallace 1948 (Box 118)
    - Straight, Michael (New Republic), 1951-1954 (Box 15)
    - Strand, Mark, 1981 (Box 111)
    - Strode, George, 1980s (Box 111)
    - Surliuga, Victoria, 1990s (Box 102)
    - Susnik, Marjetica 1996 (Box 1)
    - Szefel, Lisa, 1995, 2002 (Box 102)
    - Tate, Allen, 1949, 1978 (Box 105)
    - Teschke, Holger, 1996-2002 (Box 6, 47)
    - Thomas, Norman, 1953-1964 (Box 105)
    - Thompson, Dorothy, 1949-1973 (Box 105)
    - Timenchik, Roman, 1990s (Box 44)
    - Trevor-Roper, Hugh, 1956 (Box 105)
    - Trilling, Diana, 1950-1977 (Box 105)
    - Tyrmand, Leopold, 1979 (Box 106)
    - Untermeyer, Louis, 1948, 1972 (Box 105)
    - Vaget, Hans, 1990s (Box 44)
    - Valenti, Michelle, 2002 (Box 6)
    - Van Doren, Mark, 1951-1954 (Box 105)
    - Van Nostrand, D., 1975 (Box 104)
    - Van Rees, Iris, 1960s-1970s (Box 105)
    - Vansittart, 1940-1950s (Box 105)
    - Viereck, Anna, 1972 (Box 9, 44)
    - Von Moltke, Freya, 1961 (Box 66)
    - Wagner, Winifred, 1947-1970 (Box 104)
    - Wakowski, Diane, 1960s-1980s (Box 103)
    - Walcott, Derek, 2000 (Box 102)
    - Waller, John, 1949-1952 (Box 105)
    - Warren, Robert Penn, 1979, 1987-1990 (Box 102,118)
    - Washburn, Katharine, 1990s (Box 44)
    - Weinstein, Michael, 1990s (Box 96)
    - Weissbort, Daniel, 1979 (Box 4, 18)
    - Wells, Henry W., 1950 (Box 105)
    - Wernick, Bob, 1978, undated (Box 105)
    - Wheelock, John Hall, 1962-1978 (Box 105)
    - White, Margaret Ann Rusk, 1988-1991 (Box 108)
    - Whitman, Walt, 1950s-1980s (Box 103)
    - Wilbur,Richard (Dick), 1951-1992 (Box 118)
    - Will, George F, 1978 (Box 66)
    - Wilson,Edmund, 1965 (Box 118)
    - Williams, Miller, 1998 (Box 63)
    - Williams, W. C., 1949-1950 (Box 103, 118)
    - Wolfe, Alan, 2004 (Box 34)
    - Wolfe, Bernard, 1950s-1970s (Box 91, 105)
    - Wronoski, John--Lame Duck Books, 2004 (Box 34)
    - Yoken, Mel, undated (Box 111)
    - Zays, Ernie, 1992 (Box 105)
    - Postcard from Colleague, 1989 (Box 14)
    - Correspondence regarding Joseph Ellis's Fabricated Vietnam Stories, 2001 (Box 7)
    - General, 1953-2005 (Box 35, 52, 56, 63-66, 71-74, 76-78, 80, 83-90, 94, 98, 101-103, 105-106, 108, 110-111, 113-114,119-120)
    - Postcard Album, undated (Box 70)
    - "Important Letters"--Multiple Correspondents, 1950s (Box 20)
    - "Anti-Nazi Germany" Letters, 1961 (Box 113)
    - Letters from Former Students and Acquaintances, 1951-1993 (Box 10, 44, 63)
    - Correspondence Regarding Essay "Disturber and Restorer," 1980 (Box 10)
    - Letters with Colleagues about George Heym, 1980 (Box 15)
  - Subseries I.2: Institutions and Subjects, 1936-2005
    Subseries 2 is arranged alphabetically by the first word of the institutional name or by topic.
    - Academic International Press, 1974 (Box 63)
    - Agni, 1999 (Box 63)
    - Alfred A Knopf Publishers, 2001 (Box 20)
    - American Civil Liberties Union, 1948 (Box 106)
    - American Embassy in Italy, 1982 (Box 103)
    - American Poetry Review, 1975-1997 (Box 63, 94, 113)
    - American Spectator, 1977-1978 (Box 63)
    - Asimov, 1983 (Box 64)
    - Athenium, 1974 (Box 63)
    - Atlantic Monthly Press, 1979-1982 (Box 63)
    - Ballilol College, 1936 (Box 52)
    - Berghahn Books, 1998 (Box 113, 117)
    - Bibliographisches Institut, 1978-1987 (Box 111)
    - Bobbs-Merrill Company, Inc. 1975 (Box 111)
    - Brandeis University, 1980 (Box 113)
    - Breit, Peter K., 1989-1996 (Box 113)
    - College Street Journal, 2002 (Box 20)
    - Columbia University Press, 1979, 1991 (Box 113)
    - Commonweal, 1979 (Box 113)
    - Confrontation, 1985 (Box 113)
    - Contract with Transaction, 2004 (Box 20)
    - Copyrights, 1971 (Box 113)
    - Cornell University Press, 2002 (Box 5)
    - Crosscurrents, 1984 (Box 113)
    - Dickey Publishers, 1956-1999 (Box 52)
    - Dictionary of American Biography, undated (Box 111)
    - Dictionary of Literary Biography, 1979-1980 (Box 111)
    - D. Van Nostrand Co., 1961 (Box 14)
    - Encounter Magazine, 1962-1974 (Box 113)
    - Encyclopedia Britannica, 1974-1975 (Box 65)
    - Epoch, 1987 (Box 113)
    - Five College Consortium, 2000s (Box 102)
    - Formalist, 2000 (Box 111)
    - Gale Research Inc., 1994 (Box 113)
    - Gil Moody Magic Lantern Books, 1975-1979 (Box 113)
    - Giulio Einaudi, 1955-1963 (Box 113)
    - Globe Bookshop, 1986 (Box 113)
    - Goethe Institute Boston--German Cultural Center for New England, 1970s-1980s (Box 113)
    - Grove Press, 1993 (Box 113)
    - Guggenheim Memorial Foundation, 1948-1954 (Box 113)
    - Harper and Row Publishers, Inc., 1980 (Box 113)
    - Harvard University, 1964-1975 (Box 117)
    - Haverford, 1977-1985 (Box 111)
    - Helicon Nine Editions, 1996-1998 (Box 111)
    - Hellas, 1985-1989 (Box 113)
    - Herald Tribune, 1991 (Box 113)
    - Hitler, undated (Box 102)
    - Holt, Rinehart and Winston, Inc., 1988 (Box 113)
    - Hoover Institution, 1967-1968 (Box 113)
    - Horace Mann, 1989-2000 (Box 64, 108)
    - Houghton Mifflin Company, 1977-1984 (Box 113)
    - Hungarian Anthology (publishing), 2004 (Box 19)
    - Idaho Commission of the Arts, 1990-1991 (Box 113)
    - International Advisory Council, circa 1960s-1970s (Box 106)
    - International Communication Agency, 1981 (Box 63)
    - Italian Press, 1955 (Box 77)
    - John Hopkins Medical Institutions, 1990s (Box 113)
    - Journal of the History of Ideas, 1947 (Box 111)
    - Kenyon Review, 1978-2000 (Box 98, 113)
    - Krieger Publishing Company, Inc., 1984 (Box 113)
    - Library of Congress, 1956-1992 (Box 77, 105)
    - Libris Publisher, 2004 (Box 20)
    - Los Angeles Times, 1987 (Box 113)
    - Louisiana State University Press, 1971-1985 (Box 9)
    - The MacDowell Colony, Inc, 1990s (Box 107)
    - Macmillan Publishing Co., Inc., 1967-1984 (Box 113)
    - MagazineLine, 2002-2003 (Box 113)
    - Massachusetts Review, 2002-2003 (Box 7)
    - McFarland & Co., Publisher, undated (Box 20)
    - Michigan Quarterly Review, 1978-1983 (Box 7)
    - Michigan--University Microfilms International, undated (Box 113)
    - Modern Age, 1987-1990 (Box 113)
    - Mount Holyoke, 1984-1995 (Box 63-64, 74, 95)
    - National Review, 1980 (Box 104)
    - New American Library, 1961 (Box 105)
    - New Criterion, 1998-2004 (Box 18)
    - The New England Poetry Club, 1980s-1990s (Box 104)
    - New Hampshire, circa 1980s (Box 107)
    - New Letters, 1980s-1990s (Box 104)
    - New York Quarterly, 1970s-1980s (Box 105)
    - New York Times, 1970s-1980s (Box 49)
    - Nexus Press: Roy Chernus (Box 105)
    - Poets and Writers, 1988 (Box 91)
    - Prairie Schooner, 2003 (Box 18)
    - Radio Liberty Committee, 1960s (Box 106)
    - Rosenfeld, Meyer, and Susman, 1970s (Box 105)
    - Starline Magazine, 1986 (Box 64)
    - State Department, 1951-1977 (Box 63-64)
    - Taurus Books, 1970s (Box 105)
    - Translation Center, 1978-1980 (Box 113)
    - University Press of Washington D.C., 1950s (Box 98)
    - University of California Press, 2002 (Box 7)
    - University of Massachusetts, Amherst College, 1980s (Box 110)
    - University of Missouri-Kansas City, 1984-1985 (Box 113)
    - Van Nostrand, 1960s-1970s (Box 98)
    - Virginia Center for the Creative Arts, 1983-1997 (Box 108)
    - War Department, 1943 (Box 77)
    - World Book, 1987 (Box 111)
    - Writer's Colony--Other Members, 1972-1982 (Box 111)